Claudia Cecilia Rossi



claudiarossi0707@gmail.com

https://resume-ccr.herokuapp.com/ (user:guest, pass:1234) https://www.linkedin.com/in/claudiaceciliarossi/ US permanent residence Visa. Citizenship and passports: Argentinian and Italian

Profile

I have over twenty years of experience in software development. Working in both, face to face and virtual environments, I have covered several roles in which I was able to get adapted to the dynamics of the different changes in programming, offering to my employers the capacity and initiative of self-learning and on-the-job training. I have always strived to be able to meet the expectations of different customers.

I stopped working to be a full time mother when my only daughter was around 2 years old. And three years ago I started training, preparing myself in new technologies (.NET, Angular, Node.js) to enter the labor market again.

I was living in Argentina until now, and my family and I are relocating to the US, in the Reston area.

Major Achievements

- Led the analysis, development, training and implementation of the Personnel Performance Evaluation system for the Public mining company of Chile, CODELCO, which had 17,000 employees at that time.
- As project manager, led a multidisciplinary team responsible for the banking website: <u>www.e-galicia.com</u>, the first bank website in Argentina.

Employment History

Freelance programmer.

Aug 2011 - Aug 2014

<u>IACA Laboratories. Bahia Blanca, Arg.</u> Visual Basic developments to import and process data generated by Bioanalytical Laboratory Instruments for subsequent analysis and delivery of reports to ANMAT state organization. Trained in GLP (Good Laboratory Practices). Worked with Visual Basic.

Advanced application programmer. Remote

Mar 2006 – Mar 2010

BA Technology. Bahía Blanca, Arg. CODELCO, the public mining company of Chile, had RHPro software. We had to customize the performance development module, to fit with CODELCO's requirements. I was responsible for the requirements analysis and for the development. Later, I facilitated the training, including both Headquarters in Santiago Chile and a mine in El Salvador. Once project was completed, I was responsible for the maintenance of it. Worked with: ASP (VBScript), HTML, JavaScript, MS-Sql Server, Visual Studio.

Assistant programmer.

Mar 2005 – Feb 2006

<u>Solvay. Bahía Blanca, Arg.</u> Temporary replacement of IT personnel in the HR Area. Main responsibilities were maintenance of database and macro developments in Visual Basic for Excel. This information was used for the performance development. Worked with: Visual Basic.

WEB software developer. Remote.

Jan 2001 – Mar 2005

RHPRO (Heidt & Asociados). Buenos Aires, Arg. Application scheduler for INTRANET. Customization of an existing HR management system to meet customers' requirements. I worked remote from home, doing the customizations development and I traveled to Buenos Aires many times to do the analysis requirements, for example for Deloitte Argentina, Acetera General Deheza, Cargill, Los Grobo, Farmacity among others. Worked with: ASP (VBScript), HTML, JavaScript, MS-Sql Server, Oracle, Visual Studio.

Project Manager.

May 1998 – Mar 2001

<u>Technisys. Buenos Aires, Arg.</u> Leader of WEB projects. Tasks consisted of interviews with clients, requirements analysis, planning, work team organization and also applications programming. In the 2000s with the emergence of web technology, I was able to lead the development many important websites like Fondos1784 (Bank Boston) and www.e-galicia.com (Galicia Bank). Worked with: ASP (VBScript), HTML, JavaScript, MS-Sql Server, Oracle, Visual Studio.

Lieutenant - Data Computing Service.

Mar 1996 – Apr 1998

<u>Argentina Army. Bahía Blanca, Arg.</u> Development of ammunition inventory stock control applications for the "Base de Apoyo Logistico (BAL)" military unit in Pigue. Worked with: Clarion programming language.

Advanced application programmer. Remote

Jun 1993 – Mar 1996

<u>Systems Solutions. Buenos Aires, Arg.</u> Senior programmer in the 4th generation Progress language, for installation, maintenance and customizations of the Magnus Datasul system. Programming in sequential Progress and afterward in version 7 and higher ones, consequently changing the paradigm to event-driven programming.

Develop and facilitate Progress 7 training, aimed to programmers who filled positions in Joinville (Brazil) and Canale and Danone (Argentina). I worked remote and traveled for implementations and tests at Mastellone, Quest International, Campo Frio and Elf Lubricants, among others. Worked with: Progress language and Progress4GL language.

Assistant Professor

Mar 1992 – Dec 1994

<u>Universidad Nacional del Sur. Bahía Blanca, Arg.</u> Assistant Professor A (graduate) in the following courses: "Introduction to Computing", "Data Processing", "Algorithm Structures" and "Programming Languages"

Skills and Competences

- Build strong interpersonal relationship with Customers. Understand and meet their needs.
- High ability to self-learning in new technologies.
- High experience in remote work.
- Deliver training to multifunctional teams.

Education and training

- Bachelor Degree in Computer Science. Universidad Nacional del Sur, Bahia Blanca. 1984 1990
- Diploma in C # .NET. Sep 2018 Dec 2018. UTN FRBA e-Learning Center
- Angular programming. Jun 2019 Jul 2019. UTN FRBA e-Learning Center
- Node Js programming. Oct 2019 Nov 2019. UTN FRBA e-Learning Center
- Professional Webmaster. March 2021-Sept 2021. UTN FRBA e-Learning Center
- 1st Certificate English level. 1973 1983 Asociación Bahiense de Cultura Inglesa.
- IELTS Intensive preparative course. March 2021 April 2021. www.ielts.org.ar

Personal information

For family needs, I resided, in 2008, three months in Baton Rouge, Louisiana, United States. In 2010, I lived three months in Rayon, Thailand. In 2018, spent one month in Houston, United States. All these cases gave me the opportunity to enhance my English skills and exposed me to personal relationship with people from different cultures.

References

- Mrs. Lila Drittanti, PhD. (+33 (0)7 82 25 1958) linkedin.com/in/liladrittanti/ Paris, France.
 www.markets-listing.com. ldrittanti@gmail.com
- Mrs. Virgina Cuomo, BSc (+54 9 11 51111782). Founder IkiGo. Buenos Aires, Argentina.
 vvcuomo@hotmail.com.
- Mrs. Monica Wirth, CEH IT Service Management Head at BankUnited, SVP. Fort Lauderdale, FL USA monica. wirth@gmail.com.
- Mr. Pablo Sametband, VP Sales and Partner at Baufest, Argentina. Pablo.sametband@gmail.com